<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/index.html</link>
    <description>This is your new home page.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ci Cd</title>
      <link>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/ci-cd/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/ci-cd/index.html</guid>
      <description>This is a new chapter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conatiner</title>
      <link>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/container/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/container/index.html</guid>
      <description>This is a new chapter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Editor</title>
      <link>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/editor/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/editor/index.html</guid>
      <description>A source-code editor is a text editor program designed specifically for editing source code of computer programs. It may be a standalone application or it may be built into an integrated development environment (IDE).&#xA;Source-code editors have features specifically designed to simplify and speed up typing of source code, such as syntax highlighting, indentation, autocomplete and brace matching functionality. These editors also provide a convenient way to run a compiler, interpreter, debugger, or other program relevant for the software-development process. So, while many text editors like Notepad can be used to edit source code, if they do not enhance, automate or ease the editing of code, they are not source-code editors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Version Control System</title>
      <link>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/vcs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dev-maz.github.io/swe-tools/vcs/index.html</guid>
      <description>Version control (also known as revision control, source control, and source code management) is the software engineering practice of controlling, organizing, and tracking different versions in history of computer files; primarily source code text files, but generally any type of file.&#xA;Version control is a component of software configuration management.&#xA;A version control system is a software tool that automates version control. Alternatively, version control is embedded as a feature of some systems such as word processors, spreadsheets, collaborative web docs, and content management systems, e.g., Wikipedia’s page history.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>